Two strangers made friends by a savage land. Two
friends made enemies by the civilized world.
Mountains of the Moon is a adventure, drama,
history film directed by Bob Rafelson.
The story of Captain Richard Francis Burton's and Lt.
John Hanning Speke's expedition to find the source of the Nile
river in the name of Queen Victoria's British Empire.
Richard Burton, played by Patrick Bergin.
John Hanning Speke, played by Iain Glen.
Oliphant, played by Richard E. Grant.
Isabel, played by Fiona Shaw.
Lord Murchison, played by John Savident.
Lord Oliphant, played by James Villiers.
Mountains of the Moon is a 1990 American biographical film depicting the 1857–1858 journey of Richard Francis Burton and John Hanning Speke in their
expedition to Central Africa, which culminated in Speke's discovery of the source of the Nile River and led to a bitter rivalry between the two men.
The film stars Patrick Bergin as Burton and Iain Glen as Speke.
Delroy Lindo appears as an African whom the explorers meet.
The film was directed by Bob Rafelson based on the 1982
novel Burton and Speke by William Harrison.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
africa, river, expedition, nile.
The tone is emotional.